Now, we'll build upon the previous risk model by
现在 我们将在之前的风险模型中
including two additional factors for a total of three.
再添加两个因子 一共有三个因子
This is the famous Fama-French model,
这就是有名的 Fama-French 模型
which can be considered the model that started the movement towards multi-factor models.
它是多因子模型的基础
The original three-factor Fama-French model includes the market return,
原始三因子 Fama-French 模型包含市场收益率
and adds two additional factors,
另外两个因子
which the other's called size and value.
分别是市值和价值
Let's look at these two additional factors,
我们来看看这两个因子
and how the data for them are generated.
并了解如何生成这两个因子的数据
The first additional factor we will look at is size.
首先来看看市值
The size of a company is measured by its market cap.
公司市值 (size) 用公司的市值 (market cap) 表示
There's been evidence that shows,
有证据表明
that small-cap companies have higher average returns compared to large-cap companies.
小盘股的平均收益率比大盘股的高
In other words, if we can determine that company ABC is a small-cap stock,
假设 ABC 是一个小盘股
valued at one billion dollars, and company XYZ,
市值为 10 亿美元
is a large cap stock valued at $10 billion,
XYZ 是一个大盘股 市值为 100 亿美元
then we could expect that company ABC will have
那么预计公司 ABC 的风险调整后收益率
higher risk adjusted returns, compared to XYZ.
将比 XYZ 的高
The question is how much more return can we expect for company
问题是 如果 ABC 的市值只是 XYZ 的一部分
ABC for being a fraction of the size of XYZ?
ABC 预计收益率会高出多少？
Remember that we're trying to fill in the factor risk model.
我们要填充因子风险模型
The factor covariance matrix uses the time series of factor returns for
因子协方差矩阵使用以下三个因子的因子收益率时间序列：
the three factors: market, size and value.
市场收益率 市值和价值
Well, if you had evidence,
如果你能证明
that small cap stocks had higher than average returns,
小盘股的平均收益率比大盘股的高
than large-cap stocks, what would you do as
作为一名理性投资者
a rational investor to make use of this knowledge?
你会如何利用这一经验？
One way that seems to make sense is to buy small-cap stocks,
一种合理策略是买入小盘股
and to short large-cap stocks.
并做空大盘股
If we had a portfolio in which you bought small-cap stocks and shorted large-cap stocks,
如果我们在投资组合中买入小盘股并做空大盘股
we could track the portfolio's value over time so we'd have a time series.
那么可以跟踪投资组合随时间推移的价值 即时间序列
We could also calculate the daily return on this portfolio.
还可以计算此投资组合的每日收益率
The return of this portfolio is the return of the size factor.
这个投资组合的收益率是市值因子的收益率
Let's think about what this portfolio tells us.
我们来看看这个投资组合的结果
If the portfolio's return is positive,
如果投资组合的收益率为正
it means that on that day,
那么表示在这一天
favoring small cap stocks had a positive effect on the portfolio's return.
偏向于小盘股对投资组合的收益率有正面影响
If the portfolio's return is negative,
如果投资组合的收益率为负
then it means that on that day,
那么表示在这一天
favoring small cap stocks had a negative effect on the portfolio's return.
偏向于小盘股对投资组合的收益率有负面影响
So that's pretty cool.
太酷了
We have a way of quantifying whether a smaller size
我们能够量化更小的市值
actually adds to positive or negative returns on each day.
在每一天对收益率有正面还是负面影响